We're now going to look at something that allows you to make your programming a bit more exciting and
almost a bit more personal for your user, because at the moment, I mean, we've been using print,
but, you know, that's like when it's all output, we need some input.
So let's go ahead and look at input.
You know, you meet those people that are all just talk.
Never give you a moment.
Yeah.
Well that's what's been prints all about.
Just talk talk talk.
Time for you to get some input.
Okay, so luckily with Python, they've made this very easy for us.
So where before we had let's just let's put in a print statement.
Print.
Hello.
We can now do use input.
So again we just type in input.
And now basically whatever you put inside these brackets is actually what is going to print on the screen.
So it's almost as if you're asking a question.
Okay.
So let's ask the user what their name is.
So what is your name.
Yeah.
What's your name.
Okay, so now it's.
What?
As I said, whatever you put in here is the question.
And it gives you now this little flashing cursor, which means you can tap inside the shell now.
So my name is Sarah.
And then I just went and printed whatever the user typed.
So if you'd let's just run it again and print something else.
What is your name?
Okay, Craig.
And it's just gone ahead and printed Craig.
So that's not too exciting.
But I mean, it is, it is taking what the user has typed in and it's read it and it now knows the user's
name is Craig.
It's pretty happy now.
Okay.
But we don't just want to read a name and let it be printed out.
We actually want to do something with this.
Yeah, we need to store it somewhere.
So now let's what are those things called those variables?
Yeah, exactly.
I knew these variables had a good reason for existing.
Not just for storing shoes and cars and turkeys.
It is enough.
Off stored money.
I've stored this question well.
I've stored the answer to this question inside the variable, my name.
So it might be a little bit confusing.
You would think this is storing this whole thing input.
What is your name?
But my name is not storing this.
It's storing whatever the user types.
So again you'll see what is your name.
If I then go and type Sarah it's not going to do anything.
But what Python has actually done is it's taken this value, Sarah, as a string and stored it inside
my name.
So we could have a look inside that my name variable and have a little quiz and see what's stored inside
there.
So using our print statement we now want to print money and see what it is actually storing.
So let's consider a different name Molly okay let's do Molly.
Wow that's so cool.
So now without changing the actual code of the program.
We can keep running this program and typing in new inputs, and those are being stored, so you can
immediately see what's happening now.
The code no longer needs to change.
That remains the same.
That variable is holding a value.
And so the user can input that value and it is stored in that variable.
And this is where the power of variables is now starting to come in.
Because we can input things into them or the user can input values into the variable.
So say you were creating a game and a lot of games might ask you to enter your name.
They can make the game seem a bit more personalised to you.
So let's just say you asked for the user's name and then you want to say hello to them.
So remember it's the hello.
And then if you want to add a new thing into the print statement, you just put in that comma.
So now what is your name?
Danny.
It's going to tell you.
Hello, Danny.
So it's taken whatever that user typed and stored it in this variable, my name and printed it out here.
And just remember, whatever the user types here is taken as a string.
So even if I had gone and typed my name as being eight, it says hello eight.
But this is not a number, this is a string.
Anything the user inputs is taken by Python as being a string.
So you can have so much fun here.
You want to have some fun.
You want to make yourself feel good.
Do this.
Simply make a small change and then hit run.
Type your name and hit enter.
Oh, I feel so fantastic.
And you can keep running it over and over and over again and make yourself feel great.
Isn't this programming amazing?
Oh, no.
This is why it makes you feel good about yourself.
You could do just about anything.
Okay, so that was a quick look at it.
It is also a very powerful thing.
We will be using it a lot later.
And yeah, go ahead, have some more fun with it.
Try out different things and start programming.